PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- I know, I know I promised you I'd give you a chance
- 好啦 我知道啦 我会给你一个
to sit in my chair.
坐在我凳子上的机会的
Well, now I think you're finally ready.
好吧 现在我觉得你终于准备好了
One of the final polishing steps in making a film
做一部电影最后的美化
is the final color adjustments to every single frame
就是对电影的每一帧进行最终的色彩调整
of the film, in order to increase its impact
用于增加对观众的
on the audience.
冲击力
And that's exactly what we do here
这就是我们在这里
in the color mastering suite,
这个调色室里做的事情
but it's not actually me who does it.
但是这并不是由我来操作的
Let me introduce you to our colorist, Mark Dinicola.
就由我来向你们介绍我们的调色师 Mark Dinicola
Hi, Mark.
嗨 Mark
- Hi, Don, thank you for having me.
- 嗨 Don 谢谢你邀请我
- Great, so tell me what is your job?
- 真棒 快来告诉我你的工作是什么？
- I operate this color mastering system.
- 我操作这套调色系统
It's the tool set of a colorist, and a colorist
它是调色师的工具箱
is responsible for actually making all adjustments
而调色师的责任就是最后实际操刀
to a finished film.
完整电影的最终调整
I could show you an example on Ratatouille.
我可以给你看一个《料理鼠王》的例子
- Cool.
- 太酷了
- So if we take this shot from Ratatouille, for example,
- 我们从料理鼠王中抽出这个镜头 举例来说
we might start by adding contrast,
我们会先从增加对比度开始
then we might add some saturation.
然后是增加一些饱和度
Normally when I do this, the DP is sitting here with me,
一般当我做这些东西的时候 DP 都会和我坐在一起
and on this film, the DP was Sharon Calahan.
就这部电影来说 DP 是 Sharon Calahan
Perhaps we should ask Sharon to come in.
也许我们应该让 Sharon 进来
Hey Sharon!
嘿 Sharon！
- Hey guys, what's up?
- 嘿 伙计们 怎么啦？
- So on Ratatouille, what were some of the issues
- 所以在《料理鼠王》中 你在对它的调色中
and interesting facts that came up while you were doing
都遇到了什么问题
color correction on that movie?
或者有趣的事实呢？
- Well, Ratatouille was a film that had
- 好吧 《料理鼠王》是一部具有
a very unique, stylized look to it
非常独特画面风格的电影
that we envisioned in the very beginning,
我们从一开始就是如此预期的
and a lot of it is just kinda carrying it all the way
其后的绝大部分工作都是一直追求它
through to make sure the final product
保证最后的作品
looks as good as it can and has that vision in it.
看起来尽可能好 并与预期相符
And for Ratatouille, some of those things were
对于《料理鼠王》 有些场景具有
having nice, rich shadows, making sure that
精致且丰富的阴影 保证了
there's adequate contrast and saturation in the scene,
场景中有充足的对比和饱和度
making sure the eye looks where it's supposed to look.
确保观众的双眼盯在应该看的地方
But stylistically, one of the things that was really
就技法上来看 对我来说
important to me was making the human skin look good
重要的是让人物的皮肤好看
and the food look really good,
让食物看起来非常诱人
and tying it all together, and one of the ways
有一种方法可以让它们同时出现
that I use color correction to help with that
我在调色时
is to add a little bit of red to the darks,
会向暗色部分加入一点点红色
the deep darks, so that it kind of tied the look together
就是那些非常暗的部分 这样让两者搭配的非常好
and almost made the film feel like it was
几乎让电影看起来像是
dipped in chocolate a little bit.
有一点点浸在巧克力里面
- Very cool.
- 太酷了
- I wanted the audience to leave feeling hungry.
- 我想让观众离场时带着饿意
- So guys, in this next exercise, we're gonna give you
- 好啦 同学们 在下一个练习中 我们将给你
a chance to make some of your own color adjustments
一个机会在这些场景中做出
on these scenes.
你们自己的调色
To make changes to the entire image, press select + all.
如果要对整个画面调色，按 Select all
And to adjust hue and saturation, and lightness,
用这些滑动条调整
and contrast, you can use these sliders.
色相、饱和度、亮度和对比度
We like using sliders because it allows us to make
我们喜欢用滑动条 因为它们让我们
very fine-tuned adjustments.
做出非常细致的调整
And instead of making changes to the whole image,
除了对整个场景做出调整
you can also select smaller regions in the image
你也可以仅选出一小部分
to focus on.
来细调
To do this, press select region, and then click
要这样做按下 Select region
around the image to define an area you want to adjust,
让后单击图像来定义一个你想调整的区域
like this.
比如这样
Once you've made a selection, your adjustments
一旦你做了一个选区 你对
to hue, saturation, and lightness, and contrast
色相、饱和度、亮度和对比度的调整
will only affect what's inside this region,
就只会影响选区中的区域
and anything outside it will be ignored.
而不会对外部产生任何影响
Go ahead and see what kinds of looks you can come up with.
去试一下看看你都能调整出什么样的画面来
Remember, the goal is to have fun
记住哦 一定要玩的开心
and explore what's possible. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
并探索各种可能 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox